Heather Bjoin

Minneapolis, MN 55403 h.m.bjoin@gmail.com 309-371-0868

Github

https://github.com/HeatMarie

<u>Linkedin</u>

https://www.linkedin.com/in/heather-bjoin-bb833761/

<u>Portfolio</u>

https://heatmarie.github.io/portfolio/

"Never forget how much you enjoy coding." Those were words expressed to me from a client as I finished cutting his hair after a long talk about my experience in the Coding Bootcamp at the U of M. I enjoy the challenges given with each project and each new technology I have learned. I find them engaging and fulfilling, even more so when I have to struggle to get the final result. My ideal work environment would be a place where I get utilizing my full stack skills, working from the UI to the server. I would find greater value in a workplace where there are other developers who share my enthusiasm and have a desire to continue to learn.

PROJECTS

Poggers-POG (Plan on Gaming)

Two weeks

Poggers-POG is an app that allows users to sign into an account and add game titles and tasks to those goes. This was a full stack group project that utilized Handlebar templates, Express.js, Sequelize, MySQL, and Heroku.

https://poggers-pog.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/HeatMarie/poggers

Blitz and Chaos (An Interactive Story)

Two weeks

Blitz and Chaos is an interactive story app that allows the reader to dive further into a story by making their own choices. This app used APIs, JavaScript, CSS, HTML5 to give the user the experience of an Interactive Story.

https://heatmarie.github.io/BlitzandChaos/ https://github.com/HeatMarie/BlitzandChaos

The Tech Blog

Two weeks

This fun, pesky project was one to put all the skills to the test. The project implemented Handlebar templates, Express.js, Sequelize, MySQL, and Heroku to truly create a full stack app.

https://heats-tech-blog.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/HeatMarie/techBlog

SKILLS

- Node.js Express.js React.js MySQL MongoDB
 - JavaScript APIs JSON Responsive Design CSS HTML5

EXPERIENCE

GREAT CLIPS | WINDJAMMERS

Cosmetologist

Minneapolis MN June 2019 - present

As a cosmetologist at Great Clips I ensure that each customer receives a quality experience and a quality haircut. It's all about great customer service, and being able to thoroughly communicate with every customer to ensure their satisfaction. In addition to helping customers, it's also essential to keep a clean salon. Together the staff works as a team, to make sure that our salon meets and exceeds the states requirements for cleanliness by following the sanitation guidelines.

GREAT CLIPS | PB5

Cosmetologist / Manager

Galesburg IL | Macomb IL Aug. 2011 - Feb. 2017 | Oct. 2017 - June 2019

While working for PB5 (Great Clips) I was a hair stylist, and a manager. As manager, my tasks went beyond that of a stylist. I motivated my team to stay on task, made weekly schedules for the stylist, haircut training, and ensured customer satisfaction.

REGISTER-MAIL

Reporter (intern)

Galesburg IL March - May 2019

As an intern at the Register-Mail I was able to get involved and write articles on several community events. Towards the end of my internship I had my own column that focused on good deeds that happened within the community.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF MINNESOTA

Full Stack Web Development Certificate Oct 2021

CARL SANDBURG COLLEGE

Associates of Arts 2019